Okay, now that we know what Git is,
let's talk about how we would install it
on a Mac. On a Mac, it's actually pretty
easy. You're going to hit command space
and then type terminal. And then you're
going to hit enter. And it's going to
open up this terminal. And I'm going to
try and increase the font size. Um, all
right.
What you're going to want to do is
you're going to want to type the word
get and d- version. When you run that,
some of you will see a version, and that
means you already have Git installed and
there's nothing left to do. The rest of
you will um see this popup here that
asks if you want to install um the
command line developer tools. So, I'm
going to click install. I'm going to
agree to Apple's terms
and continue on battery power. Probably
should have done this plugged in. Oh
well. Says there are 15 hours. It
shouldn't actually take that long, but I
am going to pause until it's done.
Okay. So you can see I started this at
like 11:26, maybe 11:27, and it's only
11:34. So it actually didn't take that
long, but it is now done. So we'll hit
done. Now, if we come here and we type
get, you can see that it says everything
that you can do with Git. So if you can
type get on your command line and you
see all of that, congratulations, you've
installed Git. There's a couple of
things you're going to want to do in
order to make sure your Git runs
properly. The first is you're going to
want to type get config dash global
space user.name. And here's where you're
going to want to put your username. I'm
going to put Toa. Then you're going to
type get config-
global user.mail. And this is email is
probably going to be the one you're
going to probably want to put the one
that you use on GitHub. So I'm going to
type uh to teaches techgmail.com
and hit enter.
Once you've done that, you're good to
go. You've got to get installed on your